# JAGRAJ SINGH

(206) 304-3009 | jagrajs@icloud.com | in/jagrajs | jag.ai

## **ABOUT**

Experienced retail sales professional transitioning into data science and artificial intelligence.

Currently pursuing a data analyst role where I can apply my educational experience and analytical skills to be a great asset to your company.

Utilizing various online resources to expand skills in computer science and advanced mathematics to match market demand.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Product Advisor 2018 - Present

**Microsoft** | Bellevue, WA

- Demonstrate Microsoft products and services to help customers achieve more.
- Generate business leads to increase store revenue.
- Diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve common technical issues.
- Deliver workshops and personal trainings to educate and inspire clients.

#### Freelance Data Scientist

2018 - Present

**Self-Employed** | Seattle, WA

- Cryptocurrency Lottery
  - Building a Bitcoin & Ethereum Lottery program based on cryptographic principles using Python.
- Closing Apéry's Constant
  - Testing new attack vectors and attempting to solve a 375 year old problem in analytic number theory using linear algebra and Python.

### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Arts in Communications** | University of Washington

2014 - 2017

• Coursework included advanced public speaking and a concentration in mathematics.

# **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages**: Python (2 years), SQL (1 year) Tools: NumPy, SymPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, MATLAB, Octave

Markup & Web: LaTeX, HTML, CSS

Productivity: Microsoft Office 365 (Word, Excel, Powerpoint, OneNote, Outlook)

Knowledge of advanced mathematics including linear algebra and statistics.

**Languages**: English (fluent), Punjabi (working proficiency)

US Citizen